# **Kamlesh Pandey**

kpandey@ncsu.edu | +1 (984) 810-9759 | Raleigh, 27606 | LinkedIn | Website

#### **SUMMARY**

Master student at North Carolina State University, planning to concentrate on optimization modeling and data science. Skilled in Python, TensorFlow, R with work experience of six years as Supply chain planner and optimization analyst.

Actively looking for Summer 2022 internships.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Industrial Engineering North Carolina State University, Raleigh Aug 2021 – May 2023

GPA-3.11/4.0

**Bachelor of Technology**, Mechanical Engineer Dehradun Institute of Technology, Dehradun

Aug 2011 - May 2015 Percentage:75.5/100

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Supply Chain Optimization Analyst, NewAge Product Inc. Mumbai,

Feb 2021-Aug 2021

- Optimized container loading plans using Cubmaster solver to maximize space utilization, saved an average of two 40" high cube containers per month
- Identification and prioritization of inbound shipment related issues at 13 distribution centers across the USA and Canada
- Achieved more than 90% of accuracy in the Item Master Data/ Product specification database of non-garage SKUs
- Monitored inventory level at 13 distribution centers and flagged overstock, out-of-stock and slow-moving inventory
- Inventory audit of non-garage SKUs at each warehouse level

## Supply Chain Planning Manager, Reliance Industries Ltd. Mumbai

June 2015 – Feb 2021

- Served as a logistic planner & scheduler of oil tanker loads across RIL's rail and coastal terminals with daily product sale of 190 TKL
- Over 90% database accuracy of five oil marketing companies' customer master database
- Configured Trading/dispatch location units including vendor creation, product configuration, and plant creation, currently strategically located 44 locations pan India
- Provided Master Data Management (MDM), Inventory Management, and material requirement planning services to five government and private companies
- Averaged 70 rail rakes/ 180 TKL product movement from Jamnagar refinery to three hinterland rail terminals
- Delivered purchase requisition orders for 44 active dispatch units fortnightly basis using SAP MM module, average 90-100 TKL purchase per month

### **PROJECT**

### • Terminal SAP Integration

~RIL'2017

Integration of oil tanker loading process from rail and coastal terminals with SAP, provided interactive web-based portal for indent creation, tracking and, scheduling, led to cycle time reduction by average  $30 \, \text{min}$ 

• Vessel Scheduling Model with Profit Point (Aspen Technology Partner)

~RIL'2018

Worked with Analytical Team of Profit Point for coastal scheduling model for an optimized loading plan of 90 to 120 forward days

### • Rail Planning & Scheduling Model (Excel, What's Best Solver)

~RIL'2018

Scheduling model for product movement via rakes, generating wagon and location combinations as decision variables after meeting all loading constraints

Pan India BSIV to BSVI Conversion

~RIL'2020

Operational planning and scheduling for pan India BSIV to BSVI conversion of rail gantry and dispatch units

## • Reliance BP Mobility Ltd. Company Configuration

~RIL'2020

Created customer master database of 1400+ retail outlets of RBML, (RIL & British Petroleum join venture) in RIL's SAP system

#### **SKILL**

Program Language: Excel Python | TensorFlow Pandas NumPy Julia Matplotlib

Professional: Supply Chain Planning | Optimization | Scheduling | SAP | Demand Planning | Purchase & Sales